A breakthrough that changed the face of medicine. A
unique partnership that broke the rules.
Something the Lord Made is a tv movie, drama film directed by Joseph Sargent.
A dramatization of the relationship between heart surgery
pioneers Alfred Blalock and Vivien Thomas.
Dr. Alfred Blalock, played by Alan Rickman.
Vivien Thomas, played by Yasiin Bey.
Mary Blalock, played by Kyra Sedgwick.
Clara Thomas, played by Gabrielle Union.
Mrs. Saxon, played by Merritt Wever.
William Thomas, played by Charles S. Dutton.
Something the Lord Made is a 2004 American made-for-television biographical drama film about the black cardiac pioneer Vivien Thomas (1910–1985) and his
complex and volatile partnership with white surgeon Alfred Blalock (1899–1964), the "Blue Baby doctor" who pioneered modern heart surgery.
Based on the National Magazine Award-winning Washingtonian magazine article "Like Something the Lord Made" by Katie
McCabe, the film was directed by Joseph Sargent and written by Peter Silverman and Robert Caswell.
The film explores themes of friendship, mentor, biography,
man of one's dreams, based on true story.
The tone is uplifting and emotional.